<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <title>Creating your Device List</title>

  <para><code>CpDeviceList</code> is a protocol-independent base class.
  However, the mechanism you use to discover remote devices necessarily
  depends on the protocol being used. ohNet's UPnP implementation provides
  five <code>CpDeviceList</code> sub-classes which implement the different
  types of searches defined by UPnP.</para>

  <para>Each of these classes represents a specific way to filter your
  application's search for remote devices. The five classes are as
  follows:</para>

  <para><table>
      <title></title>

      <tgroup cols="2">
        <thead>
          <row>
            <entry align="center">Class</entry>

            <entry align="center">Description</entry>
          </row>
        </thead>

        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry><code>CpDeviceListUpnpAll</code></entry>

            <entry>All UPnP devices and all services currently available on
            those devices.</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry><code>CpDeviceListUpnpRoot</code></entry>

            <entry>All root UPnP devices — that is, the single device that
            contains one or more other UPnP devices.</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry><code>CpDeviceListUpnpUuid</code></entry>

            <entry>A specific device given a universally unique name by the
            vendor (note this is not the same as the friendly name
            attribute).</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry><code>CpDeviceListUpnpDeviceType</code></entry>

            <entry>All devices that correspond to the UPnP device type (note
            that this can be taken from the UPnP Forum's published list of
            devices or as a new device that you have defined).</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry><code>CpDeviceListUpnpServiceType</code></entry>

            <entry>All services that correspond to the UPnP service type (note
            that this can be taken from the UPnP Forum's published list of
            services or as a new service that you have defined).</entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table></para>

  <para>Choose which type of search you want to use in your application and
  create your new Device List object. For example:</para>

  <programlisting>CpDeviceListCppUpnpServiceType* list = new 
    CpDeviceListCppUpnpServiceType(domainName, serviceType, ver, added, 
        removed);</programlisting>

  <note>
    <para>The example used above specifies the domain, service type and
    version of the service. These details are required for this particular
    Device List and must be declared in the body of your Control Point
    application code. See the API for the details of each Device Lists'
    arguments.</para>
  </note>

  <para>You can now use the <code>CpDevice</code> objects to create Proxies to
  allow your Control Point application to communicate with the remote
  device.</para>
</section>
