<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <title>Introduction</title>

  <para>This document is for developers using the OpenHome ohNet stack to
  publish a device's services over a local network.</para>

  <para>ohNet is a full UPnP stack. The public APIs are protocol independent
  and offered in C++, C# and C.</para>

  <note>
    <para>All code examples in this document use C++. Each C++ function used
    has an equivalent in the other languages. The naming scheme for the
    functions is consistent between the languages so you can easily find the
    functions in the other languages published in the API.</para>

    <para>All snippets also assume the use of two namespaces:
    <code>OpenHome</code> and <code>OpenHome::Net</code>.</para>
  </note>

  <para>The Device stack exposes the parts of ohNet required to present your
  device's services to interested clients, such as Control Points.</para>

  <para>Specific emphasis is placed on the use of Providers to publish
  services, giving access to the actions and properties that define each
  service. To help you write your Provider, ohNet comes supplied with the
  tools needed to automatically generate code from the service XML. This
  document includes details on how to use the generation tool and a detailed
  walk-through of how to write a Provider using example code.</para>

  <note>
    <para>You must have detailed knowledge of how the services are implemented
    on your device. The code generated for the Provider gives you a framework
    which you can add to. You must add the code in the Provider to fully
    implement each service's action.</para>
  </note>

  <xi:include href="Introduction-Prerequisites.xml" xpointer="element(/1)" />

  <xi:include href="Introduction-RelatedDocuments.xml" xpointer="element(/1)" />

  <xi:include href="Introduction-WhyChooseOhNet.xml" xpointer="element(/1)" />
</chapter>
